A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers FA108
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Office and Homes Files, 1928-1978 1955-1978; 3; 40 Cubic Feet 115 Boxes
  - Philanthropy and Public Interests, 1937-1978 1952-1978; 3
    The bulk of this subseries is devoted to materials relating to the work of organizations and commissions founded by Rockefeller to address issues of concern to him. One of Rockefeller's earliest involvements was as chair of a Boys Bureau committee that studied the causes of juvenile delinquency. "Youth in the Toils" (folders 242-243), the culmination of the committee's six years of effort, was published in 1938. Also in this subseries are files relating to Colonial Williamsburg (folders 248-250). Rockefeller worked closely with his father on this restoration project, which is evidenced by their correspondence (folder 249). Rockefeller's involvement with the Rockefeller Foundation (folders 322-334) and with the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (folders 311-320) is also documented here.
    Material that complements the Lincoln Center files in series 1 can be found in this subseries (folder 285-290). Of particular note is a 1977 interview conducted with Rockefeller adviser Edgar B. Young on JDR 3rd's role in the development of Lincoln Center. Rockefeller was also instrumental in the establishment of the Rockefeller Archive Center (folders 305-310) and the Rockefeller Public Service Awards (folders 335-343), which honor civilian employees in the Federal government. The collaborative efforts of Rockefeller, John E. Harr, Datus C. Smith, and Richard Schickel in the writing of "The Second American Revolution" are extensively documented in drafts, correspondence, and memoranda (folders 344-398).
    In addition to material on the JDR 3rd Fund and its Arts in Education Program (folders 282-284), this subseries contains a number of files on the Youth Task Force. Established by the JDR 3rd Fund in 1970 to promote understanding among youth, business, and professional leaders, the Task Force sponsored a series of dialogs and underwrote surveys by Daniel Yankelovich, Inc. (folders 427-435). As a result of Wright Patman's attacks on philanthropy, Rockefeller became a lobbyist on its behalf. Numerous elements of this subseries reflect his efforts to protect, reform, and enhance philanthropy in the United States. Related material will be found under the headings "Corporate giving" (folders 264-267); "Tax reform" (folders 399-404); and "Third sector" (folders 406-419). Rockefeller's search to find methods of partnership between philanthropy, on the one hand, and government and private enterprise on the other hand, led to the creation of the Commission on Foundations and Private Philanthropy ("Peterson Commission," folders 251-254) and the Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs ("Filer Commission," folders 254-260).
    - Agricultural Development Council - Roles of Women, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 238)
    - American Institute for Public Service, 1974-1975 (Box 42, Folder 239)
    - Anacostia Neighborhood Museum, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 240)
    - Arts - Background Material, 1965, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 241)
    - Boys Bureau - "Youth in the Toils" Study (Draft), c.1938 (Box 42, Folder 242)
    - Boys Bureau - "Youth in the Toils" Study, c.1938 (Box 42, Folder 243)
    - Center for the American Woman and Politics (Rutgers University), 1971 (Box 42, Folder 244)
    - Central Intelligence Agency and Foundations, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 245)
    - Changing National Values Study, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 246)
    - Citizens Committee for Charter Revision (New York State), 1975 (Box 42, Folder 247)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, Inc. - Racial Issue, 1946-1951 (Box 42, Folder 248)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, Inc. - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1937-1954 (Box 42, Folder 249)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, Inc. - Special Survey Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 42, Folder 250)
    - Commission on Foundations and Private Philanthropy (Peterson Commission), 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 251)
    - Commission on Foundations and Private Philanthropy (Peterson Commission), 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 252)
    - Commission on Foundations and Private Philanthropy (Peterson Commission), 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 253)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Filer Commission), 1972-1978 (Box 43, Folder 254)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Filer Commission), 1972-1978 (Box 43, Folder 255)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Filer Commission), 1972-1978 (Box 43, Folder 256)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Filer Commission) - "An Agenda for the Future", 1975 (Box 43, Folder 257)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Filer Commission) - Follow-up Activites (Box 43, Folder 258)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Filer Commission) - Report, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 259)
    - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Filer Commission) - Report, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 260)
    - Committee on the Foundation Field (Gardner Committee), 1969-1970 (Box 44, Folder 261)
    - Concern for Dying, 1977, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 262)
    - Conference on Social Research and Foreign Affairs, 1969-1970 (Box 44, Folder 263)
    - Corporate Giving, 1970-1978 (Box 44, Folder 264)
    - Corporate Giving, 1970-1978 (Box 44, Folder 265)
    - Corporate Giving - News Clips and Background Material, 1975-1977 (Box 44, Folder 266)
    - Corporate Giving - Nielsen, Waldemar A., 1977 (Box 44, Folder 267)
    - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 268)
    - Culture, Importance of, 1956, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 269)
    - Dayton Hudson Corporation, 1976-1977 (Box 44, Folder 270)
    - Election Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 45, Folder 271)
    - Foundations - Background Material, 1957, 1960, 1963-1965, 1969-1975 (Box 45, Folder 272)
    - Foundations - Background Material, 1957, 1960, 1963-1965, 1969-1975 (Box 45, Folder 273)
    - Fowler (Henry H.) Discussions, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 274)
    - Government and the Arts, 1962-1965 (Box 45, Folder 275)
    - Hampshire College, 1970-1973 (Box 45, Folder 276)
    - "Harper's Magazine" Article, 1957-1965 (Box 45, Folder 277)
    - History Project, 1974-1977 (Box 45, Folder 278)
    - History Project, 1974-1977 (Box 45, Folder 279)
    - Immigration, 1971 (Box 46, Folder 280)
    - International Women's Year Conference, 1975-1976 (Box 46, Folder 281)
    - JDR 3rd Fund - Meetings, 1972-1975 (Box 46, Folder 282)
    - JDR 3rd Fund - Meetings, 1972-1975 (Box 46, Folder 283)
    - JDR 3rd Fund - Arts in Education Program, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 284)
    - Lincoln Center - Background Material, 1956-1976 (Box 47, Folder 285)
    - Lincoln Center - Board of Directors Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 47, Folder 286)
    - Lincoln Center - Chairmanship (CLOSED FOLDER), 1976-1977 (Box 47, Folder 287)
    - Lincoln Center - Feasibility Study, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 288)
    - Lincoln Center - Repertory Theater, 1963-1965 (Box 47, Folder 289)
    - Lincoln Center - Young (Edgar B.), on Role of John Davison Rockefeller 3rd, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 290)
    - McCloy-Dillon Committee, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 291)
    - Morality and Ideals Background Material, 1957-1962 (Box 47, Folder 292)
    - Moskowitz, Milton, 1977-1978 (Box 47, Folder 293)
    - New York City Program in the Arts, 1964-1971 (Box 47, Folder 294)
    - New York City Urban Awards Program, 1967-1968 (Box 48, Folder 295)
    - Office of Newark Studies (Rutgers University), 1971 (Box 48, Folder 296)
    - Performing Arts Background Material, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 297)
    - Performing Arts Curriculum Enrichment Project, 1966-1967 (Box 48, Folder 298)
    - Performing Arts Curriculum Enrichment Project, 1966-1967 (Box 48, Folder 299)
    - Personal Notes Concerning Meetings and Conferences, 1971-1975 (Box 48, Folder 300)
    - Philanthropy, General, 1967-1968 (Box 48, Folder 301)
    - Philanthropy Discussion Group, 1966-1967 (Box 48, Folder 302)
    - Pocantico Hills - Floor & Foundation Plan- New Gatehouse for Greenrock Corp.-Pocantico Hills, NY- Map #2- #4 (Peter Ogden, Architect), 1976; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 95)
      Separated from Subseries 3: Philanthropy and Public Interest
    - Pocantico Hills - JDR Jr. Burial Lot - Pocantico Hills, NY-General Planting Plan (records show burial plots in green crayon) (red and green marker) #1, MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 95)
    - Pocantico Hills - Maps showing Pocantico Sewer District #2- Situated in Town of Mount Pleasant, Westchester Co., NY- #3 (Chas. H. Sells, Inc., Pocantico Hills), 1972 September 12 and 1973 May 22; MAP (Drawer B 2, Folder 95)
    - Pocantico Hills - Land Disposition Study- Land Disposition Study- #2 (color coded map), MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 95)
    - Pocantico Hills - Proposed Facing for Sisters' Gate, 1976; (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 95)
    - Pocantico Hills - Survey of Property prepared for JDR 3rd- Situated in North Tarrytown- Town of Mount Pleasant-Westchester Co., NY #2A, 1944 July; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 94)
    - Pocantico Hills - Survey of Property prepared for JDR 3rd- Situated in North Tarrytown- Town of Mount Pleasant-Westchester Co., NY #2, 1944 July; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 94)
    - Pocantico Hills Estate- Pocantico Hills, Town of Mt. Pleasant- Westchester Co., NY. (Chas. H. Sells Inc. civil engineers and surveyors, Pleasantville, NY), Prepared 1961 June, revised 1968 June 28. Revised 1973 January 22 and February 12; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 94)
    - Pocantico Hills - Exhibit-Rockwood Hall Site- Town of Mount Pleasant- Alternate "A" (access) road systems (William Samuel Archibald), MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 94)
    - Pocantico Park Proposal, 1972-1978 (Box 49, Folder 303)
    - Race Issues, 1953-1965 (Box 49, Folder 304)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center, 1972-1977 (Box 49, Folder 305)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center, 1972-1977 (Box 49, Folder 306)
      - H. Goldstone report, 1975 January 20 (Box P 171, Folder 33)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center, 1972-1977 (Box 49, Folder 307)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center, 1972-1977 (Box 49, Folder 308)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center - Memos, 1955-1965, 1974-1977 (Box 50, Folder 309)
    - Rockefeller Archive Center - Transfer Policy, 1975-1977 (Box 50, Folder 310)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc., 1976-1977 (Box 50, Folder 311)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Creel Committee, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 312)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Financial, 1952-1956, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 313)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - General Program, 1952-1956 (Box 50, Folder 314)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Individual Projects, 1952-1955 (Box 50, Folder 315)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Minutes, 1974-1978 (Box 50, Folder 316)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - New Procedures, 1975, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 317)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - Organization and Procedures, 1953-1956 (Box 50, Folder 318)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - "Performing Arts: Problems and Prospects", 1965 (Box 50, Folder 319)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Inc. - "Performing Arts: Problems and Prospects", 1965 (Box 51, Folder 320)
    - Rockefeller Family Fund, Inc., 1972-1977 (Box 51, Folder 321)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1957 (Box 51, Folder 322)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1957 (Box 51, Folder 323)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1957 (Box 51, Folder 324)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1957 (Box 51, Folder 325)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Board of Nominations, 1956-1957 (Box 51, Folder 326)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - President, Selection of, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 327)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - President, Selection of, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 328)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Program Notes, 1953-1955 (Box 52, Folder 329)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Reece Committee, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 330)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Reece Committee, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 331)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Reece Committee, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 332)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1946-1949 (Box 52, Folder 333)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Trustee Candidates, 1945-1947 (Box 52, Folder 334)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1972-1973 (Box 52, Folder 335)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1972-1973 (Box 52, Folder 336)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1974-1978 (Box 53, Folder 337)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1974-1978 (Box 53, Folder 338)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1974-1978 (Box 53, Folder 339)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, 1974-1978 (Box 53, Folder 340)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards - Federal Legislation, 1953-1958 (Box 53, Folder 341)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards - Luncheon, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 342)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards - McLean (Donald H.) on Role of John Davison Rockefeller 3rd, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 343)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - General, 1973-1975 (Box 53, Folder 344)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Background Material, 1969-1970 (Box 53, Folder 345)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Background Material, 1969-1970 (Box 54, Folder 346)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Comments (Box 54, Folder 347)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Distribution (Box 54, Folder 348)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Schickel (Richard) Manuscript, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 349)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Schickel (Richard) Manuscript, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 350)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Schickel (Richard) Manuscript, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 351)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Schickel (Richard) Manuscript, 1969 (Box 55, Folder 352)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Harr (John E.), 1970-1972 (Box 55, Folder 353)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Harr (John E.), 1970-1972 (Box 55, Folder 354)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Harr (John E.), 1970-1972 (Box 55, Folder 355)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Final Manuscript (Ch. 1-19) (Box 55, Folder 356)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Final Manuscript (Ch. 1-19) (Box 55, Folder 357)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Master (Ch. 1-14) (Box 56, Folder 358)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Master (Ch. 1-14) (Box 56, Folder 359)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Master (Ch. 1-14) (Box 56, Folder 360)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Master (Ch. 1-14) (Box 56, Folder 361)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Master (Ch. 1-14) (Box 56, Folder 362)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Master (Ch. 15-20) (Box 57, Folder 363)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Master (Ch. 15-20) (Box 57, Folder 364)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Second (Ch. 1-19) (Box 57, Folder 365)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Second (Ch. 1-19) (Box 57, Folder 366)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Third (Ch. 1-20) (Box 57, Folder 367)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Third (Ch. 1-20) (Box 57, Folder 368)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Final (Ch. 1-10) (Box 57, Folder 369)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Final (Ch. 11-19) (Box 58, Folder 370)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 1-9), 1971 (Box 58, Folder 371)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 11-20), May-August 1972 (Box 58, Folder 372)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 11-20), May-August 1972 (Box 58, Folder 373)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 10-20), June 1972 (Box 58, Folder 374)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 15-20), June-July 1972 (Box 58, Folder 375)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 1-10), July-September 1972 (Box 59, Folder 376)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Revisions (Ch. 1-10), July 1972 (Box 59, Folder 377)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - Revisions (Ch. 1-10), July 1972 (Box 59, Folder 378)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 1-20), September 1972 (Box 59, Folder 379)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 1-20), September 1972 (Box 59, Folder 380)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 1-20), September 1972 (Box 59, Folder 381)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts (Ch. 11-20), September-October 1972 (Box 60, Folder 382)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - John Davison Rockefeller 3rd Copy (Ch. 1-20) (Box 60, Folder 383)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - John Davison Rockefeller 3rd Copy (Ch. 1-20) (Box 60, Folder 384)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - John Davison Rockefeller 3rd Copy (Ch. 1-20) (Box 60, Folder 385)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - John Davison Rockefeller 3rd Copy (Ch. 1-20) (Box 60, Folder 386)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Drafts - John Davison Rockefeller 3rd Copy (Ch. 1-20) (Box 60, Folder 387)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Galleys (Master Proofs) (Box 60, Folder 388)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Galleys (Corrected) (Box 61, Folder 389)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Harr, John E. - Memos and Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 61, Folder 390)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Rockefeller (Blanchette) Copy (Box 61, Folder 391)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Rockefeller (Blanchette) Copy (Box 61, Folder 392)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Smith, Datus C., 1966-1970 (Box 61, Folder 393)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Smith, Datus C., 1966-1970 (Box 61, Folder 394)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Speaking Notes, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 395)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Speeches and Reports, 1963, 1968, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 396)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Speeches and Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 62, Folder 397)
    - "The Second American Revolution" (Rockefeller) - Speeches and Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 62, Folder 398)
    - Tax Reform, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 399)
    - Tax Reform, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 400)
    - Tax Reform - Testimony, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 401)
    - Tax Reform - Testimony, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 402)
    - Tax Reform - Treasury Department Report on Private Foundations (Box 62, Folder 403)
    - Tax Reform - Unlimited Deductions for Charitable Contributions, 1959-1964 (Box 63, Folder 404)
    - Technical Assistance Clearing House Proposal, 1967 (Box 63, Folder 405)
    - Third Sector - Articles and Papers, 1976-1978 (Box 63, Folder 406)
    - Third Sector - Book Project, 1977-1978 (Box 63, Folder 407)
    - Third Sector - Congressional Seminar, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 408)
    - Third Sector - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 63, Folder 409)
    - Third Sector - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 63, Folder 410)
    - Third Sector - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 63, Folder 411)
    - Third Sector - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 63, Folder 412)
    - Third Sector - Duke University Conference Proceedings, October 19, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 413)
    - Third Sector - John Davison Rockefeller 3rd Article, 1975-1977 (Box 64, Folder 414)
    - Third Sector - Lunches and Dinners, 1978 (Box 64, Folder 415)
    - Third Sector - "New York Times Magazine" Article, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 416)
    - Third Sector - Nielsen, Waldemar, 1962-1978 (Box 64, Folder 417)
    - Third Sector - "Reader's Digest" Article, 1977-1978 (Box 64, Folder 418)
    - Third Sector - Yale Project, 1975-1978 (Box 64, Folder 419)
    - United Nations Conference on Human Settlements, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 420)
    - Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1971-1973, 1976-1977 (Box 65, Folder 421)
    - Urban Home Ownership Corporation, 1971-1973, 1976-1977 (Box 65, Folder 422)
    - Women, Status of, 1975-1977 (Box 65, Folder 423)
    - WNET/Channel 13, 1972-1978 (Box 65, Folder 424)
    - WNET/Channel 13 - Review Committee, 1978 (Box 65, Folder 425)
    - Yankelovich Youth Study, 1973 (Box 65, Folder 426)
    - Youth Task Force - General, 1971-1974 (Box 65, Folder 427)
    - Youth Task Force - General, 1971-1974 (Box 65, Folder 428)
    - Youth Task Force - General, 1971-1974 (Box 65, Folder 429)
    - Youth Task Force - Background Material, 1963-1969 (Box 66, Folder 430)
    - Youth Task Force - Business Leaders Meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 66, Folder 431)
    - Youth Task Force - Business Leaders Meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 66, Folder 432)
    - Youth Task Force - Meeting, September 1970 (Box 66, Folder 433)
    - Youth Task Force - Yankelovich, Dan, 1970, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 434)
    - Youth Task Force - Youth-Establishment Dialogs, 1972 (Box 66, Folder 435)
    - Colonial Williamsburg- Mr. JDR 3rd Property; Basset Hall- Part of a Map of Williamsburg Virginia Embracing the Areas of Colonial occupation- #1., MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 98)
    - Mr. JDR 3rd Property- Bassett Hall Maps-Williamsburg map showing proposed expansion of golf course- Forest Map- #2., 1962 January 4; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 98)
    - Mr. JDR 3rd Property- Forest Map showing Wooded areas- Colonial Williamsburg- #3, 1960 July 15; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 98)
    - Mr. JDR 3rd Property- Forest Map showing Wooded areas- Colonial Williamsburg- #4, 1961 August 9; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 98)
    - Basset Hall- Sketch Study for the Locations for New Entrance Drive Lights- #5, 1965 June 2; RENDERING (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 98)
    - Colonial Williamsburg- Forest Map showing wooded areas- #6., 1962 January 4; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 98)
    - Property Ownerships in the Vicinity of the Proposed Williamsburg Southern Artery- #7, 1968 April 12; MAP (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 2, Folder 98)
  - Population Interests, 1965-1978 1970-1978; 4
    The bulk of this subseries documents Rockefeller's role in the national and international population movement during the 1970s. In 1972, President Richard Nixon appointed Rockefeller chair of the National Commission on Population Growth and the American Future. The commission, which had been created by Congress, was charged with making recommendations regarding a broad range of population issues. The work of the commission and its findings are documented in this subseries. A number of files in this subseries reveal Rockefeller's strong interest in the abortion debate, an interest that predated the Supreme Court's 1973 "Roe v. Wade" decision. After the decision, Rockefeller and Joan Dunlop, his adviser on population and on the status of women, attempted to develop strategies to influence public opinion in favor of access to contraceptive and abortion services.